- ( estática crepitante )
P
Pre
Prese
Presen
Presente
Presente Da
Día Presente
Día Presente_
P
Pre
Prese
Presen
Presente
Presente T
Presente Ti
Tiempo Presentee
Tiempo Presentee_
- ( estática crepitante )
- ( voz distorsionada )
- ♪ AND YOU DON'T SEEM
TO UNDERSTAND ♪
♪ A SHAME YOU SEEMED
AN HONEST MAN ♪
♪ AND ALL THE FEARS
YOU HOLD SO DEAR ♪
♪ WILL TURN TO WHISPER
IN YOUR EAR ♪
♪ AND YOU KNOW WHAT THEY SAY
MIGHT HURT YOU ♪
♪ AND YOU KNOW THAT
IT MEANS SO MUCH ♪
♪ AND YOU DON'T EVEN
FEEL A THING ♪
♪ I AM FALLING ♪
♪ I AM FADING ♪
♪ I HAVE LOST IT ALL ♪
♪ OHH-HH ♪
♪ OH, YEAH ♪
♪ I AM FALLING ♪
♪ I AM FADING ♪
♪ I AM DROWNING ♪
♪ HELP ME TO BREATHE ♪
♪ I AM HURTING ♪
♪ I HAVE LOST IT ALL ♪
♪ I AM LOSING ♪
♪ HELP ME TO BREATHE. ♪
- ( persone chattando )
- Girl: ENTONCES TU TAMBIEN QUIERES SUFRIR, VERDAD?
QUIERES QUE TU CORAZON
TO FEEL
LIKE IT'S BEEN SCRAPED ACROSS
WITH A RASP?
SI ES ASI, NO MIRES PARA OTRO LADO, PASE LO QUE PASE.
- ESTA BIEN.
NADIE PUEDE ESTAR SEGURO DE SI REALMENTE EXISTE O NO.
YA VERAS, EN SU MAYOR PARTE,
IT DOESN'T REALLY MATTER TO
THE USER IF GOD ACTUALLY EXISTS
IN THE WIRED.
PREGUNTALES. NO LES IMPORTA.
UH, HEY, JUST A SECOND
THERE, LAIN.
BEFORE YOU GO, LET ME TAKE
THIS GUY OUT FIRST.
- QUE TIENE DE DIVERTIDO ESTO, TARO?
TODO LO QUE HAS HECHO ES MATAR A TODOS LOS OTROS JUGADORES.
- NOBODY REALLY KNOWS
QUE ES DIVERTIDO.
AND SO NO ONE CAN REALLY
UNDERSTAND WHY.
- HMM.
THE NAME THAT WAS WRITTEN
ON THE DOOR PLATE WAS
"TACHIBANA GENERAL
LABORATORIES."
- ( voz masculina ) A COMPANY
AS BIG AS TACHIBANA GENERAL LABS
WOULD NEVER DREAM
OF DOING ANYTHING ILLEGAL.
I'VE HEARD SOME RUMORS
THOUGH.
- RUMORES?
- IN THE WIRED,
DO YOU HAVE ANY IDEA
HOW WE'RE ABLE TO EXCHANGE
INFORMATION LIKE THIS?
- OH, SO YOU THINK
ME ESTAS PROBANDO, NO?
I KNOW YOU'RE TALKING
ABOUT THE I.P., AREN'T YOU?
- ( risa )
PERDON, TIENES RAZON.
WE RARELY KNOW OF
THE PROTOCOL'S EXISTENCE,
ESPECIALLY WITH
THE ADVANCED LEVELS.
HOWEVER, THE SIXTH-GEN PROTOCOL
HAS REACHED
ITS ABSOLUTE DATA THROUGHPUT
LIMIT, AS FAR AS WE CAN TELL.
- ENTONCES ES EL PROTOCOLO DE SEPTIMA GENERACION.
- YES, THE SEVENTH-GEN PROTOCOL.
BIG COMPANIES ARE THE ONES
MAKING IT INTO
THE NEW INFRASTRUCTURE.
YA VERAS, CONTROLAR
THE PROTOCOL
MEANS TO CONTROL THE ENTIRE
ECONOMY OF THE WIRED
WITHOUT ANY INTERFERENCE.
ESCUCHO QUE HAY CONSTANTES
SABOTAGE ATTEMPTS GOING ON.
AND THE PARTY
BEHIND ALL THIS IS...
- LABORATORIOS GENERALES TACHIBANA.
- ( risa )
- ESTAS BIEN, MIKA?
- YO-- YO--
( murmurando )
( mumbling )
- MOMMY, DADDY,
CAN I ASK--?
A WHILE AGO SOME--
SOMEBODY ASKED ME
A STRANGE QUESTION.
ME PREGUNTARON,
"ERES LAIN IWAKURA?"
AND THEN THEY ALSO
WANTED TO KNOW,
"ARE YOUR PARENTS
REALMENTE TUS PADRES?"
NO ES GRACIOSO?
ES GRACIOSO, NO?
LA GENTE DICE LAS COSAS MAS GRACIOSAS, NO?
VERDAD?
- ( chicas chattando )
- OH MY GOSH, YOU LOOK SO GOOD.
Girls: HEY.  SO GOOD
TO SEE YOU.
VAS A IR A VER
THIS MOVIE AFTERWARDS?
- EH?
OH, HI, ALICE.
GOOD MORNING.
QUE PASA?
QUE PASA, ALICE? DIME.
- NO SE.
SOLO QUE NO LO CREO.
- EH?  WHAT?
BELIEVE WHAT?
- LAIN, TU NO LO HICISTO.
- NO HICE QUE?  EH?
- APUESTO QUE HA ESTADO ACTUANDO DE INOCENTE SOLA.
- REIKA, NO LO SABES
FOR SURE.
- EN SERIO, QUIERES DECIR QUE NO FUE TU, LAIN?
- WHAT ARE YOU
TALKING ABOUT?
- LAIN, EN EL WIRED,
TU--?
NO, NEVER MIND.
FORGET ABOUT IT.
IT COULDN'T HAVE BEEN YOU, LAIN.
IT'S ALL RIGHT.
I TRUST YOU, OKAY?
- UH, ALICE.
- EH?
( gasps )
- HEY, ALICE.
- ( girls laughing )
- ( voces susurrando )
- ( voz masculina )
IT'S JUST TOO DANGEROUS.
WE HAVE TO AVOID
APPROVING ANY MORE BILLS.
- ( voz femenina )
I CAN'T BELIEVE IT.
HOW COULD SUCH A NICE GUY
GET HIMSELF INTO
SUCH A COLLECTION
OF WEIRD STUFF?
- ( voz masculina )
THERE'S AN EXTREMELY SERIOUS BUG
THAT HAS BEEN DETECTED
IN PROTOCOL SIX.
EL DAÑO CAUSADO POR ESTO PUEDE SER CATASTROFICO EN EL WIRED.
- YOU HAVEN'T HEARD
THE BEST PART-- EVERY NIGHT
A CHILDLIKE PERSON IN
A RED-AND-GREEN STRIPED SWEATER
APPEARS IN HER ROOM.
- WHEN SHE WAS IN HIGH SCHOOL,
THAT POP SINGER HIT SOMEONE
WITH HER BOYFRIEND'S CAR.
AND THEN SHE JUST
FLED THE SCENE.
- I TELL YOU THAT
IT'S GOTTA BE TRUE.
I HEARD ALL THE INFORMATION
FIRSTHAND.
- ( risa ) THE BUILDING'S
A FAMOUS HAUNTED SPOT, YOU KNOW?
IF YOU LOOK AT ITS TERMINAL
AT NIGHT,
INTERNAL EMAIL SHOWS UP,
BUT NOBODY'S THERE.
- THE KNIGHTS
DON'T EXIST.
SOME AMERICAN STUDENT
STARTED IT AS A JOKE.
- CALLATE!
A QUIEN LE IMPORTA ESO?
- ( voz masculina ) DON'T YOU FIND
ANY OF IT INTERESTING?
- EH?  WHO'S THERE?
- ME ESTAS BUSCANDO, LAIN, NO ES ASI?
- ENTONCES DIOS HACE SU GRAN ENTRADA.
- PERO COMO DEFINES A TU DIOS?
IF IT'S THE CREATOR
OF THE WORLD, THAT'S NOT ME.
THE ALL-POWERFUL RULER
OF THE WORLD?
SURELY YOU ARE MISTAKEN.
YOU GIVE GOD TOO MUCH CREDIT.
- ENTONCES DONDE ESTAS TU?
- WELL, IF YOU DEFINE GOD
AS ONE WHO EXISTS EVERYWHERE
IN THAT OTHER WORLD OUT THERE--
IF THAT'S WHAT YOU MEAN,
THEN YES,
I SUPPOSE THAT
YOU COULD CALL ME THAT.
I HAVE ONLY
A SLIGHT INFLUENCE
ON THE OVERALL WORKINGS
OF THE WORLD, HOWEVER.
- QUIEN DIABLOS ERES TU?
- I AM YOU.
SURELY YOU MUST HAVE
REALIZED IT SOMETIME--
THAT ANOTHER YOU
HAS ALWAYS EXISTED
ON ITS OWN TERMS
HERE IN THE WIRED.
TU ERES MERAMENTE UN HOLOGRAMA DE ESE OTRO TU.
ERES ESENCIALMENTE SOLO UN CUERPO.
- ESPERAS QUE ME LO CREA?
IMPOSIBLE.
ES LOCURA.
- ( risa )
BUT YOU DON'T THINK
THAT THE YOU IN THE REAL WORLD
IS THE SAME
AS THE ONE
THAT'S STANDING HERE
IN THE WIRED, DO YOU?
- WELL, NO.
BECAUSE I'M ME.
I'M ME.
- ( dispositivo vibrando )
Tommy el Voyeur
- ALICE.
ALICE, WHERE ARE YOU?
ALICE.
ALICE, DONDE ESTAS?
ALICE, WHERE ARE YOU?
ALICE?
WHAT DID I--
WHAT DID I DO?
WHAT DID I DO
IN THE WIRED?
QUE ESTA HACIENDO EL OTRO YO MIENTRAS ESTOY SENTADA AQUI?
NO TE PREOCUPES POR LOS RUMORES! NO TE PREOCUPES!
- ARE YOU SURE
IT IS ALL RIGHT
FOR YOU TO BE DOING THIS
WITH A TEACHER?
- NO, IT'S NOT.
- SO THEN WHY ARE YOU
DOING IT?
WON'T YOU GET
INTO TROUBLE?
- PORQUE QUIERO.
( gasps )
- ( risita )
QUE VERGUENZA, ALICE.
DIME, TIENES ALGUNA IDEA DE QUIEN LE GUSTA A ALICE MIZUKI?
AND DO YOU HAVE ANY IDEA
WHO SHE'S THINKING OF
WHEN SHE PLAYS
WITH HERSELF?
- THEY WERE RIGHT.
IT WAS YOU WHO TOLD
EVERYONE, WASN'T IT?
THE RUMORS THAT WERE GOING
AROUND SCHOOL WERE TRUE.
- ( risita )
- LAIN!
YOU'VE ALWAYS BEEN SITTING THERE
QUIETLY, JUST WATCHING ME.
VISTE LO QUE NO QUERIA QUE NADIE SUPIERA SOBRE
CUANDO NO QUERIA QUE NADIE VIERA LO QUE HACIA AQUI.
AND THEN WHEN I--
- ( riendo )
- TELL ME.  IT CAN'T BE.
LAIN, TELL ME.
LAIN.
YOU DECEIVED ME!
- ( música animada sonando )
- ( riendo )
- WHO ARE YOU?
YOU'RE NOT ME.
THERE'S JUST NO WAY.
I'D NEVER DO THE KIND OF THINGS
THAT YOU'VE BEEN DOING.
- OH, SPARE ME.
- JUST STOP IT.
WHY ARE YOU ACTING LIKE
THE PART OF ME THAT I HATE?
I WISH YOU WOULD
JUST GO AWAY.
- ( risita )
- TE VOY A MATAR.
- LOOK AT ME.
I'M COMMITTING SUICIDE.
( laughing )
- POR QUE-- POR QUE ESTAS TAN CALIENTE?
WHY IS IT?  WHY DO I HAVE
TO FEEL YOUR BODY HEAT?
IS THERE NO ESCAPING YOU?
- BUT HOW CAN YOU?
SOY LAIN COMO TU LO ERES, NO ES ASI?
- NO!  NO!
- ( riendo )
- QUE DIABLOS?
QUE SON ELLOS?
- ( voz masculina )
THEY'RE ALL YOU.
I SAID THAT YOU'VE ALWAYS
EXISTED IN THE WIRED, DIDN'T I?
- YES.
- YOU'RE EXACTLY THE SAME AS ME.
YOU'RE OMNIPRESENT
IN THE WIRED
FOREVER.
WHEREVER ANYONE IS,
WHEREVER THEY GO,
YOU HAVE ALWAYS
BEEN THERE.
HAS VISTO LO QUE NO PERMITIERON QUE LOS OTROS VIERAN.
YOU'VE TOLD EVERYONE
ABOUT IT, THAT'S ALL.
IT WAS THE RIGHT THING
TO DO.
DON'T WORRY.
THE WIRED'S INFORMATION
SHOULD BE SHARED, SHOULDN'T IT?
- ALL OF IT--
ALL YOU'VE SAID--
IT'S A LIE.
- WHY IS THAT?
- ALICE AND ALL OF THE OTHERS--
THEY SAID THAT THEY SAW ME
IN THE WIRED
WHEN I KNOW
I WASN'T THERE.
WHAT REALLY MATTERS IS THAT
AS LONG AS I'M AWARE OF MYSELF,
MY TRUE SELF IS ALWAYS
RIGHT HERE INSIDE OF ME.
YOU'RE TELLING ME
THAT YOU'VE BEEN PASSING OFF
THESE DUPES AS ME
ALL ALONG?
QUE MONTON DE BASURA.
IF I'M REALLY--
IF I'M REALLY
WHAT YOU SAY I AM,
AND I'M TOTALLY DELUDED,
THEN--
- ENTONCES QUE, LAIN?
- ALL THEIR MEMORIES
OF BEING SEEN BY LAIN--
I COULD PERHAPS DELETE
THAT INFORMATION.
- THAT'S TRUE.
GIVE IT A TRY.
YOU WERE BORN WITH THAT KIND
OF POWER INSIDE OF YOU.
- ( chicas chattando, riendo )
- Chica: ESTARE POR LOS CASILLEROS DESPUES.
- Girl #2: NO, OF COURSE NOT.
- Girl #1: SEE YA.
- Alice: LAIN!
- ( risita )
- HEY LAIN, WAIT UP.
- ( voz de Lain ) COULD THEY
REALLY HAVE FORGOTTEN?
- ( riendo )
- OLVIDARON?
- LAIN.
- THEY REALLY DID.
- ALICE.
QU-- QUE?
QUE DIABLOS--?
- ALICE.
HEY, I WANT TO GO
TO CYBERIA TODAY.
COME ON, LET'S GO.
- ( risita )
- I SECOND.
- THIS IS UNUSUAL.
- SURE, WE CAN GET CHANGED
AT MY PLACE AGAIN
AND GO FROM THERE.
- GREAT.
HEY, ALICE, QUE PIENSAS QUE DEBERIA USAR?
- PARA ESTO!
ALICE, ESTOY AHI! SOY YO!
I'M OVER HERE, ALICE.
- Julie: COME ON, HURRY UP.
- Reika: HEY, WAIT FOR ME.
- THAT'S RIGHT.
IT'S JUST LIKE YOU SAID--
LAIN IS LAIN
AND I AM ME.
- HOLA, NAVI.
- HOLA, LAIN.
- I AM ME.
I'M THE ONLY ME, VERDAD?
AND THERE ISN'T ANY OTHER ME
BUT ME.
ISN'T THAT VERDAD?
- ( canción temática sonando )
nan no tsumi mo nai hazu na no ni nanraka no batsu wo uketeru
Although I must be innocent, now I am punished
jibun de maita tane de mo nai no ni
I wasn't the one who sowed those seeds, but nevertheless
sakimidareta hana tsumasareru
I have to pull up the flowers that bloomed from them
shiranai koto to mo ienai ga
I can't say I didn't know about it
katabou katsuida oboe wa nai
but I don't remember taking any part in it
jiyuu wo takaku kawasareta ki mo suru ga
I think my freedom cost me dearly
kokoro made yasuku utta oboe wa nai
but I don't remember selling my soul so cheaply
hey hey kutabatte osaraba suru made
Hey hey, until I die and say farewell...
hey hey dare no te ni mo kakaranai
Hey hey... no one can touch me
tooi yoru wo urotsuiteiru
You probably don't know
shiranai darou eien no narazu monotachi wo
the eternal outlaws prowling in the distant night