- (estática crepitante)
P
Pre
Prese
Presen
Presente
Presente Da
Día Presente
Día Presente_
P
Pre
Prese
Presen
Presente
Presente T
Presente Ti
Tiempo Presente
Tiempo Presente_
- (estática crepitante)
- ( distorted speech )
- ♪ AND YOU DON'T SEEM
TO UNDERSTAND ♪
♪ A SHAME YOU SEEMED
AN HONEST MAN ♪
♪ AND ALL THE FEARS
YOU HOLD SO DEAR ♪
♪ WILL TURN TO WHISPER
IN YOUR EAR ♪
♪ AND YOU KNOW WHAT THEY SAY
MIGHT HURT YOU ♪
♪ AND YOU KNOW THAT
IT MEANS SO MUCH ♪
♪ AND YOU DON'T EVEN
FEEL A THING ♪
♪ I AM FALLING ♪
♪ I AM FADING ♪
♪ I HAVE LOST IT ALL ♪
♪ OHH-HH ♪
♪ OH, YEAH ♪
♪ I AM FALLING ♪
♪ I AM FADING ♪
♪ I AM DROWNING ♪
♪ HELP ME TO BREATHE ♪
♪ I AM HURTING ♪
♪ I HAVE LOST IT ALL ♪
♪ I AM LOSING ♪
♪ HELP ME TO BREATHE. ♪
- ( people chattering )
- Girl: so you want
TO BE HURT TOO, DO YOU?
DO YOU WANT YOUR HEART
TO FEEL
LIKE IT'S BEEN SCRAPED ACROSS
WITH A RASP?
IF YOU DO, DON'T LOOK AWAY,
WHATEVER YOU DO.
- OKAY.
NOBODY CAN BE SURE
IF THERE REALLY IS OR NOT.
YOU SEE,
FOR THE MOST PART,
IT DOESN'T REALLY MATTER TO
THE USER IF GOD ACTUALLY EXISTS
IN THE WIRED.
YOU ASK THEM.  THEY DON'T CARE.
UH, HEY, JUST A SECOND
THERE, LAIN.
BEFORE YOU GO, LET ME TAKE
THIS GUY OUT FIRST.
- WHAT'S SO FUN
ABOUT THIS, TARO?
ALL YOU'VE BEEN DOING IS
KILLING ALL THE OTHER PLAYERS.
- NOBODY REALLY KNOWS
WHAT'S FUN.
AND SO NO ONE CAN REALLY
UNDERSTAND WHY.
- HMM.
THE NAME THAT WAS WRITTEN
ON THE DOOR PLATE WAS
"TACHIBANA GENERAL
LABORATORIES."
- ( male voice ) A COMPANY
AS BIG AS TACHIBANA GENERAL LABS
WOULD NEVER DREAM
OF DOING ANYTHING ILLEGAL.
I'VE HEARD SOME RUMORS
THOUGH.
- RUMORS?
- IN THE WIRED,
DO YOU HAVE ANY IDEA
HOW WE'RE ABLE TO EXCHANGE
INFORMATION LIKE THIS?
- OH, SO YOU THINK
YOU'RE TESTING ME, HUH?
I KNOW YOU'RE TALKING
ABOUT THE I.P., AREN'T YOU?
- ( chuckles )
SORRY, YOU'RE RIGHT.
WE RARELY KNOW OF
THE PROTOCOL'S EXISTENCE,
ESPECIALLY WITH
THE ADVANCED LEVELS.
HOWEVER, THE SIXTH-GEN PROTOCOL
HAS REACHED
ITS ABSOLUTE DATA THROUGHPUT
LIMIT, AS FAR AS WE CAN TELL.
- SO IT'S THE SEVENTH-GEN
PROTOCOL.
- YES, THE SEVENTH-GEN PROTOCOL.
BIG COMPANIES ARE THE ONES
MAKING IT INTO
THE NEW INFRASTRUCTURE.
YOU SEE, TO CONTROL
THE PROTOCOL
MEANS TO CONTROL THE ENTIRE
ECONOMY OF THE WIRED
WITHOUT ANY INTERFERENCE.
I HEAR THAT THERE'S CONSTANT
SABOTAGE ATTEMPTS GOING ON.
AND THE PARTY
BEHIND ALL THIS IS...
- TACHIBANA GENERAL LABS.
- ( chuckles )
- YOU OKAY, MIKA?
- I'M-- I'M--
( mumbling )
- MOMMY, DADDY,
CAN I ASK--?
A WHILE AGO SOME--
SOMEBODY ASKED ME
A STRANGE QUESTION.
THEY ASKED,
"ARE YOU LAIN IWAKURA?"
AND THEN THEY ALSO
WANTED TO KNOW,
"ARE YOUR PARENTS
REALLY YOUR PARENTS?"
ISN'T THAT FUNNY?
IT'S FUNNY, ISN'T IT?
PEOPLE SAY
THE FUNNIEST THINGS, HUH?
RIGHT?
- ( girls chattering )
- OH MY GOSH, YOU LOOK SO GOOD.
Girls: hey.  so good
TO SEE YOU.
ARE YOU GONNA GO SEE
THIS MOVIE AFTERWARDS?
- HUH?
OH, HI, ALICE.
GOOD MORNING.
WHAT'S WRONG?
WHAT'S WRONG, ALICE?  TELL ME.
- I DON'T KNOW.
IT'S JUST I DON'T BELIEVE IT.
- HUH?  WHAT?
BELIEVE WHAT?
- LAIN, YOU DIDN'T DO IT.
- DIDN'T DO WHAT?  HUH?
- I'LL BET SHE'S BEEN
PLAYING INNOCENT ALL ALONE.
- REIKA, YOU DON'T KNOW THAT
FOR SURE.
- SERIOUSLY, YOU MEAN TO SAY
IT WASN'T YOU, LAIN?
- WHAT ARE YOU
TALKING ABOUT?
- LAIN, IN THE WIRED,
DID YOU--?
NO, NEVER MIND.
FORGET ABOUT IT.
IT COULDN'T HAVE BEEN YOU, LAIN.
IT'S ALL RIGHT.
I TRUST YOU, OKAY?
- UH, ALICE.
- HUH?
( gasps )
- HEY, ALICE.
- ( girls laughing )
- ( voices whispering )
- ( male voice )
IT'S JUST TOO DANGEROUS.
WE HAVE TO AVOID
APPROVING ANY MORE BILLS.
- ( female voice )
I CAN'T BELIEVE IT.
HOW COULD SUCH A NICE GUY
GET HIMSELF INTO
SUCH A COLLECTION
OF WEIRD STUFF?
- ( male voice )
THERE'S AN EXTREMELY SERIOUS BUG
THAT HAS BEEN DETECTED
IN PROTOCOL SIX.
DAMAGE CAUSED BY THIS MAY PROVE
DISASTROUS IN THE WIRED.
- YOU HAVEN'T HEARD
THE BEST PART-- EVERY NIGHT
A CHILDLIKE PERSON IN
A RED-AND-GREEN STRIPED SWEATER
APPEARS IN HER ROOM.
- WHEN SHE WAS IN HIGH SCHOOL,
THAT POP SINGER HIT SOMEONE
WITH HER BOYFRIEND'S CAR.
AND THEN SHE JUST
FLED THE SCENE.
- I TELL YOU THAT
IT'S GOTTA BE TRUE.
I HEARD ALL THE INFORMATION
FIRSTHAND.
- ( laughs ) THE BUILDING'S
A FAMOUS HAUNTED SPOT, YOU KNOW?
IF YOU LOOK AT ITS TERMINAL
AT NIGHT,
INTERNAL EMAIL SHOWS UP,
BUT NOBODY'S THERE.
- THE KNIGHTS
DON'T EXIST.
SOME AMERICAN STUDENT
STARTED IT AS A JOKE.
- SHUT UP!
WHO CARES ABOUT ANY OF THAT?
- ( male voice ) DON'T YOU FIND
ANY OF IT INTERESTING?
- HUH?  WHO'S THERE?
- YOU'RE LOOKING FOR ME, LAIN,
AREN'T YOU?
- SO GOD MAKES
HIS GRAND ENTRANCE.
- BUT HOW DO YOU DEFINE
YOUR GOD?
IF IT'S THE CREATOR
OF THE WORLD, THAT'S NOT ME.
THE ALL-POWERFUL RULER
OF THE WORLD?
SURELY YOU ARE MISTAKEN.
YOU GIVE GOD TOO MUCH CREDIT.
- SO THEN
WHERE ARE YOU?
- WELL, IF YOU DEFINE GOD
AS ONE WHO EXISTS EVERYWHERE
IN THAT OTHER WORLD OUT THERE--
IF THAT'S WHAT YOU MEAN,
THEN YES,
I SUPPOSE THAT
YOU COULD CALL ME THAT.
I HAVE ONLY
A SLIGHT INFLUENCE
ON THE OVERALL WORKINGS
OF THE WORLD, HOWEVER.
- WHO IN THE HELL
ARE YOU?
- I AM YOU.
SURELY YOU MUST HAVE
REALIZED IT SOMETIME--
THAT ANOTHER YOU
HAS ALWAYS EXISTED
ON ITS OWN TERMS
HERE IN THE WIRED.
YOU ARE MERELY A HOLOGRAM
OF THAT OTHER YOU.
YOU ARE ESSENTIALLY
JUST A BODY.
- YOU EXPECT ME
TO BELIEVE THAT?
IMPOSSIBLE.
IT'S CRAZY.
- ( chuckles )
BUT YOU DON'T THINK
THAT THE YOU IN THE REAL WORLD
IS THE SAME
AS THE ONE
THAT'S STANDING HERE
IN THE WIRED, DO YOU?
- WELL, NO.
BECAUSE I'M ME.
I'M ME.
- ( device buzzing )
Peeping Tom
- ALICE.
ALICE, WHERE ARE YOU?
ALICE.
ALICE?
WHAT DID I--
WHAT DID I DO?
WHAT DID I DO
IN THE WIRED?
WHAT'S THE OTHER ME DOING
WHILE I'M SITTING HERE?
Don't worry about the rumors! Don't worry about it!
- ARE YOU SURE
IT IS ALL RIGHT
FOR YOU TO BE DOING THIS
WITH A TEACHER?
- NO, IT'S NOT.
- SO THEN WHY ARE YOU
DOING IT?
WON'T YOU GET
INTO TROUBLE?
- BECAUSE I WANT TO.
( gasps )
- ( giggling )
SHAME ON YOU, ALICE.
SAY, DO YOU HAVE ANY IDEA
WHO ALICE MIZUKI LIKES?
AND DO YOU HAVE ANY IDEA
WHO SHE'S THINKING OF
WHEN SHE PLAYS
WITH HERSELF?
- THEY WERE RIGHT.
IT WAS YOU WHO TOLD
EVERYONE, WASN'T IT?
THE RUMORS THAT WERE GOING
AROUND SCHOOL WERE TRUE.
- ( giggling )
- LAIN!
YOU'VE ALWAYS BEEN SITTING THERE
QUIETLY, JUST WATCHING ME.
YOU SAW WHAT I DIDN'T WANT
ANYBODY TO KNOW ABOUT
WHEN I DIDN'T EVER WANT ANYBODY
TO SEE WHAT I WAS DOING IN HERE.
AND THEN WHEN I--
- ( laughing )
- TELL ME.  IT CAN'T BE.
LAIN, TELL ME.
LAIN.
YOU DECEIVED ME!
- ( upbeat music playing )
- ( laughing )
- WHO ARE YOU?
YOU'RE NOT ME.
THERE'S JUST NO WAY.
I'D NEVER DO THE KIND OF THINGS
THAT YOU'VE BEEN DOING.
- OH, SPARE ME.
- JUST STOP IT.
WHY ARE YOU ACTING LIKE
THE PART OF ME THAT I HATE?
I WISH YOU WOULD
JUST GO AWAY.
- ( giggling )
- I'LL KILL YOU.
- LOOK AT ME.
I'M COMMITTING SUICIDE.
( laughing )
- WHY-- WHY ARE YOU
SO WARM?
WHY IS IT?  WHY DO I HAVE
TO FEEL YOUR BODY HEAT?
IS THERE NO ESCAPING YOU?
- BUT HOW CAN YOU?
I'M LAIN JUST LIKE YOU ARE,
NOW AREN'T I?
- NO!  NO!
- ( laughing )
- WHAT THE HELL?
WHAT ARE THEY?
- ( male voice )
THEY'RE ALL YOU.
I SAID THAT YOU'VE ALWAYS
EXISTED IN THE WIRED, DIDN'T I?
- YES.
- YOU'RE EXACTLY THE SAME AS ME.
YOU'RE OMNIPRESENT
IN THE WIRED
FOREVER.
WHEREVER ANYONE IS,
WHEREVER THEY GO,
YOU HAVE ALWAYS
BEEN THERE.
YOU'VE WATCHED WHAT THEY DIDN'T
ALLOW ANY OF THE OTHERS TO SEE.
YOU'VE TOLD EVERYONE
ABOUT IT, THAT'S ALL.
IT WAS THE RIGHT THING
TO DO.
DON'T WORRY.
THE WIRED'S INFORMATION
SHOULD BE SHARED, SHOULDN'T IT?
- ALL OF IT--
ALL YOU'VE SAID--
IT'S A LIE.
- WHY IS THAT?
- ALICE AND ALL OF THE OTHERS--
THEY SAID THAT THEY SAW ME
IN THE WIRED
WHEN I KNOW
I WASN'T THERE.
WHAT REALLY MATTERS IS THAT
AS LONG AS I'M AWARE OF MYSELF,
MY TRUE SELF IS ALWAYS
RIGHT HERE INSIDE OF ME.
YOU'RE TELLING ME
THAT YOU'VE BEEN PASSING OFF
THESE DUPES AS ME
ALL ALONG?
WHAT A LOAD
OF GARBAGE.
IF I'M REALLY--
IF I'M REALLY
WHAT YOU SAY I AM,
AND I'M TOTALLY DELUDED,
THEN--
- THEN WHAT, LAIN?
- ALL THEIR MEMORIES
OF BEING SEEN BY LAIN--
I COULD PERHAPS DELETE
THAT INFORMATION.
- THAT'S TRUE.
GIVE IT A TRY.
YOU WERE BORN WITH THAT KIND
OF POWER INSIDE OF YOU.
- ( girls chattering,
laughing )
- Girl: i'll be over
BY THE LOCKERS LATER.
- Girl #2: no, of course not.
- Girl #1: see ya.
- Alice: ¡LAIN!
- ( giggling )
- HEY LAIN, WAIT UP.
- ( Lain's voice ) COULD THEY
REALLY HAVE FORGOTTEN?
- ( laughing )
- THEY FORGOT?
- LAIN.
- THEY REALLY DID.
- ALICE.
WH-- WHAT?
WHAT THE--?
- ALICE.
HEY, I WANT TO GO
TO CYBERIA TODAY.
COME ON, LET'S GO.
- ( giggling )
- I SECOND.
- THIS IS UNUSUAL.
- SURE, WE CAN GET CHANGED
AT MY PLACE AGAIN
AND GO FROM THERE.
- GREAT.
HEY, ALICE, WHAT DO YOU THINK
I SHOULD WEAR?
- STOP IT!
ALICE, I'M OVER HERE!  IT'S ME!
I'M OVER HERE, ALICE.
- Julie: come on, hurry up.
- Reika: hey, wait for me.
- THAT'S RIGHT.
IT'S JUST LIKE YOU SAID--
LAIN IS LAIN
AND I AM ME.
- HELLO, NAVI.
- HELLO, LAIN.
- I AM ME.
I'M THE ONLY ME, RIGHT?
AND THERE ISN'T ANY OTHER ME
BUT ME.
ISN'T THAT RIGHT?
- ( theme song playing )
nan no tsumi mo nai hazu na no ni nanraka no batsu wo uketeru
Although I must be innocent, now I am punished
jibun de maita tane de mo nai no ni
I wasn't the one who sowed those seeds, but nevertheless
sakimidareta hana tsumasareru
I have to pull up the flowers that bloomed from them
shiranai koto to mo ienai ga
I can't say I didn't know about it
katabou katsuida oboe wa nai
but I don't remember taking any part in it
jiyuu wo takaku kawasareta ki mo suru ga
I think my freedom cost me dearly
kokoro made yasuku utta oboe wa nai
but I don't remember selling my soul so cheaply
hey hey kutabatte osaraba suru made
Hey hey, until I die and say farewell...
hey hey dare no te ni mo kakaranai
Ey ey... nadie puede tocarme
vagando por la noche lejana
Probablemente no sabes
shiranai darou eien no narazu monotachi wo
los bandidos eternos merodeando en la noche lejana