- (estática crepitante)
P
Pre
Prese
Presen
Presente
Presente Da
Día Presente
Día Presente_
P
Pre
Prese
Presen
Presente
Presente T
Presente Ti
Tiempo Presente
Tiempo Presente_
- (estática crepitante)
- ( distorted speech )
- ♪ AND YOU DON'T SEEM
TO UNDERSTAND ♪
♪ A SHAME YOU SEEMED
AN HONEST MAN ♪
♪ AND ALL THE FEARS
YOU HOLD SO DEAR ♪
♪ WILL TURN TO WHISPER
IN YOUR EAR ♪
♪ AND YOU KNOW WHAT THEY SAY
MIGHT HURT YOU ♪
♪ AND YOU KNOW THAT
IT MEANS SO MUCH ♪
♪ AND YOU DON'T EVEN
FEEL A THING ♪
♪ I AM FALLING ♪
♪ I AM FADING ♪
♪ I HAVE LOST IT ALL ♪
♪ OHH-HH ♪
♪ OH, YEAH ♪
♪ I AM FALLING ♪
♪ I AM FADING ♪
♪ I AM DROWNING ♪
♪ HELP ME TO BREATHE ♪
♪ I AM HURTING ♪
♪ I HAVE LOST IT ALL ♪
♪ I AM LOSING ♪
♪ HELP ME TO BREATHE. ♪
- ( people chattering )
- Girl: YOU SEE, IF YOU
REALLY WANT TO RID YOURSELF
OF ALL SUFFERING, YOU SHOULD
BELIEVE THAT THERE IS A GOD.
WHETHER OR NOT YOU TRULY
BELIEVE THAT HE EXISTS,
YOU CAN BE SURE THAT GOD
IS ALWAYS BY YOUR SIDE.
- Man: NEIL ARMSTRONG
ON THE PORCH
AT 109 HOURS,
19 MINUTES...
- Male announcer: ON JULY 4th,
1947, A STRANGE AIRCRAFT
HAD CRASHED IN THE DESERT
IN NEW MEXICO, AMERICA.
THE AREA WAS CONTAINED AT ONCE
BY GOVERNMENT AGENTS.
WHAT IT ACTUALLY WAS
HAS YET TO BE PROVEN
CONCLUSIVELY.
FOR NOW, CONJECTURE
HAS BECOME FACT
AND RUMOR
HAS BECOME HISTORY.
- ( door squeaks )
- ( water splashes )
- Lain: WHO'S THERE?
- Male announcer: IN 1984,
AN ENVELOPE ARRIVED
AT THE HOME OF TV PRODUCER
JAIME SHANDERA.
THE ENVELOPE,
FROM AN ANONYMOUS SOURCE,
CONTAINED A ROLL
OF UNDEVELOPED FILM.
THE FILM CONTAINED
WHAT HAS NOW COME TO BE KNOWN
AS THE MJ-12 DOCUMENT.
ROSCOE HILLENKOETTER,
HEAD OF THE C.I.A. AT THE TIME
OF THE ROSWELL INCIDENT,
WAS AT THE TOP OF THE LIST
OF 12 MEMBERS.
IT STATED THAT THESE MEN
SIGNED A SECRET TREATY
WITH EXTRATERRESTRIALS
FROM THE SPACECRAFT
AS A SPECIAL
ORGANIZATION
ANSWERABLE ONLY
TO THE PRESIDENT.
IT IS NOW ACCEPTED THAT
PRESIDENT TRUMAN'S SIGNATURE
WAS IN FACT A FORGERY,
COPIED CAREFULLY
FROM ANOTHER DOCUMENT
WITHOUT HIS KNOWLEDGE.
NAMED AS A MEMBER
ON THE MJ-12 DOCUMENT
WAS AN M.I.T. PROFESSOR,
HEAD OF THE DEPARTMENT
OF ELECTRICAL ENGINEERING,
VANNEVAR BUSH.
- CONNECT TO THE WIRED.
HOW COULD I DO IT--
TURN SOMETHING THAT DID HAPPEN
INTO SOMETHING THAT DIDN'T?
- ( male voice )
ARE YOU LAIN?
I SEE.  I SEE.
- WAIT A MINUTE.
I DON'T EVER REMEMBER
MEETING YOU.
SO HOW IS IT
THAT YOU SEEM TO KNOW ME?
- IT'S VERY SIMPLE.
THE FLOW OF INFORMATION
DOESN'T ALWAYS GO BOTH WAYS.
YOU SEE, SINCE THE MOMENT
OF THE WIRED'S CREATION,
YOU HAVE ALWAYS
BEEN HERE.
HERE YOU ARE ALWAYS FREE
TO DO AS YOU PLEASE.
- BUT I'M NOT.
I'M TRYING TO TELL YOU
THAT THAT'S NOT ME.
- I SUPPOSE.
WELL, HOW LONG
HAVE YOU BEEN HERE THEN?
AT LEAST WE COULDN'T
HAVE BEEN HERE SINCE THIS WORLD
WAS CREATED, NOW COULD WE?
THAT WOULD BE IMPOSSIBLE.
- ( male voice #2 ) THAT HAS
NOTHING TO DO WITH IT.
IF A BEING IS REMEMBERED,
THAT PROVES THAT IT'S PART
OF A RECORD.  THE TRUTH CANNOT
BE MEASURED IN TIME AND SPACE.
- ( female voice )
THAT'S ABSOLUTELY PREPOSTEROUS.
HOW OLD DO YOU THINK
THIS LAIN GIRL IS ANYWAY?
I THINK
SHE'S STILL A CHILD.
- LET'S NOT WORRY
ABOUT ME NOW, OKAY?
- Male announcer: IN 1945,
VANNEVAR BUSH DEVELOPED
A MEMORY EXPANSION CONCEPT
CALLED "MEMEX."
IT WAS A SYSTEM
WHEREBY INFORMATION
RECORDED ON MICROFILM
WAS THEN PROJECTED DIRECTLY
ONTO A TRANSLUCENT SCREEN.
WHAT HE ENVISIONED
WAS THE COMPRESSION
AND RAPID ACCESS
OF INFORMATION.
EVEN BEFORE THE ADVENT
OF COMPUTERS,
VANNEVAR BUSH HAD ALREADY
CREATED THE BASIS
FOR OUR CURRENT
MULTIMEDIA EXPLOSION,
WHILE AT THE SAME TIME
HE WAS LEADING
THE MANHATTAN PROJECT
ATOM BOMB EXPERIMENTS.
- ( upbeat music playing )
- HUH?
( whistles )
YOU FORGOT THIS.
- HUH?
- THIS.  YOU LEFT IT
ON THE FLOOR YESTERDAY.
IF YOU DON'T NEED IT,
I'LL TOSS IT.
- ARE YOU SURE IT WAS ME
THAT LEFT THAT HERE?
- YEAH, THAT'S WHAT
I'M TRYING TO SAY.
- Male announcer: CONDUCTING
SENSORY DEPRIVATION EXPERIMENTS
USING A VARIETY
OF TECHNIQUES
SUCH AS NATIVE AMERICAN
NARCOTICS AND ISOLATION TANKS
TO PROBE THE DEPTH
OF THE HUMAN UNCONSCIOUS,
JOHN C. LILLY BELIEVED
HIS EXPERIMENTS CONNECTED HIM
TO COSMIC ENTITIES
BY WAY OF A BROAD-BASED
COMMUNICATION NETWORK.
LILLY DUBBED THE BEINGS
THAT WERE GUIDING HIM
E.C.C.O.--
EARTH COINCIDENCE
CONTROL OFFICE.
- ( dolphins chattering )
- SOON AFTERWARDS,
LILLY BEGAN WORK
ON COMMUNICATION
WITH DOLPHINS.
THESE DOLPHINS ARE
INCREDIBLE CREATURES
WHICH ARE ABLE TO CONDUCT
AN ARRAY OF WIDE-RANGE
NETWORKING EXERCISES
VIA ULTRASONIC WAVES.
- HUH?
- WHAT DO YOU WANT?
- HI THERE.
YOU PROMISED ME EARLIER.
- HUH?
PROMISED WHAT?
- THAT YOU'D GO OUT
WITH ME.
- HUH?
- WHA--?
- YOU SAID
YOU'D GO OUT WITH ME.
- WH-- WHAT ARE YOU
TALKING ABOUT?
HEY, TARO, IS THAT TRUE
WHAT SHE'S SAYING?
- DID I?
MAYBE.
- NO, YOU DIDN'T.
YOU DIDN'T.
- EVEN IF I DID,
YOU'VE CHANGED TOO MUCH.
YOU AREN'T THE YOU I WANT
TO GO OUT WITH RIGHT NOW.
OKAY, LAIN?
- TARO, YOU MORON.
- WE ARE ALL THE SAME.
I'M JUST ME.
I'M THE ONLY ME.
- HMM?
- HUH?
- AWESOME!
I CAN'T BELIEVE THAT YOU
PUT ALL OF THIS TOGETHER.
OH, OKAY.
THIS SYNCS UP WITH
THE PARALLEL PROCESSORS, RIGHT?
IT'S NOT PRETTY, BUT THAT WAY
YOU CAN KEEP EXPANDING IT.
THE NUMBER OF UPGRADES
IT CAN HANDLE IS UNLIMITED.
WHAT ARE YOU USING
AS A COOLANT?
- TARO.
- AND IS THAT
LIQUID CARBON?
- SIT DOWN OVER THERE.
- HMM?
DAMN.
- I THINK YOU KNOW
WHAT THIS IS.
- HUH?
- IT'S YOU,
ISN'T IT, TARO?
YOU'RE WITH THE KNIGHTS,
AREN'T YOU?
- YOU MUST BE
THE REAL LAIN.
- I HONESTLY DON'T KNOW
WHETHER OR NOT THERE'S
ANOTHER ME IN THE WIRED.
I CAN ONLY SPEAK
FROM MY OWN EXPERIENCES.
BUT KNOW THERE'S DEFINITELY
NO OTHER ME
THAT'S COEXISTING HERE
IN THE REAL WORLD.
YOU MUST BELIEVE ME.
THE OTHER ONE WITH A BODY
HAS ONLY APPEARED IN THE CLUB.
OUTSIDE OF THERE,
IT'S BEEN ME.
YOU ONLY NEED
TO MANIPULATE THE MEMORIES
OF THE PEOPLE THERE.
ISN'T THAT RIGHT?
- BUT I--
I JUST CAN'T.  UH...
- PLAY TRACK 44.
- ( upbeat music playing )
- ( distant music continues )
- IT'S ALMOST OVER.
IT IS, ISN'T IT?
THANK GOD.
- FINALLY,
WHILE WE STILL CAN...
- ( Mika grunting,
mumbling )
OH.
BEEP, BEEP, BEEP.
UNDERSTOOD.
NOW COMMUNICATING.
LOGGING ON.
BEEP, BEEP.
GAH-HH.
- ( music continues )
- STOP.
- ( music stops )
- IT'S NOT ME.
DAMN IT, I KNEW THE DATA
COMING INTO JJ'S PLACE
HAD THIS KIND
OF EFFECT.
I JUST DIDN'T KNOW
ALL THE SPECIFICS.
BELIEVE ME.
- TARO, IF I HAD TRIED
TO INSTALL THIS COMPUTER CHIP,
DO YOU KNOW WHAT WOULD HAVE
HAPPENED TO ME?
WOULD I HAVE KILLED MYSELF
OR GONE INSANE?
- I SAID I DON'T KNOW.
THERE'S JUST NO WAY
THAT A YOUNG KID LIKE ME
COULD BE A FORMAL KNIGHTS
MEMBER.  TO THEM, I'M JUST A--
- I WONDER
WHAT THIS WILL DO.
- IT-- IT'S--
IT'S NON-VOLATILE MEMORY.
IT'LL OVERWRITE
EXISTING MEMORIES.
I'M TELLING YOU
THE TRUTH.
- WHAT KIND OF MEMORIES?
- I-- I DON'T KNOW.
YOU KNOW, LAIN, THE KNIGHTS
AREN'T REGULAR SYSTEM CRACKERS.
THERE'S SOMETHING STRANGE
ABOUT YOU, THAT'S FOR SURE.
I SEE.  THAT'S WHY THE KNIGHTS
ARE SO INTERESTED.
THE KNIGHTS ARE
HIGHLY ADVANCED USERS
WHO ARE FIGHTING
AGAINST ALL ODDS
TO MAKE THE ONLY TRUTH THERE IS
INTO A REALITY.
- I DON'T UNDERSTAND.
WHAT ARE YOU TALKING ABOUT
WHEN YOU SAY "ONE TRUTH"?
- WELL, IT'S LIKE
I SAID,
I'M NOT ACTUALLY
A FORMAL KNIGHTS MEMBER.
THEY NEVER REALLY
EXPLAINED IT TO ME.
BUT THE ONE THING I DO KNOW
IS THAT IT'S TRUE.
THE TRUTH HAS POWER FOR THE VERY
REASON THAT IT IS THE TRUTH.
AND BECAUSE IT'S THE TRUTH, IT'S
CERTAIN THAT IT HAS TO BE JUST.
IT'S PERSUASIVE,
ISN'T IT?
WOULDN'T YOU PREFER YOUR TRUTH
LIKE THAT?
I'M GOING.
SEE YA.
I THINK MYU-MYU
IS REALLY JEALOUS OF YOU.
LATER.
- LOOK, TARO,
THANKS A LOT.
- NO PROB.  LAIN.
- HUH?
- HEY, IT'S A DATE.
AM I RIGHT?
LIKE, I'M A GUY.
I JUST HAD TO DO THAT.
- ( door opens
and closes )
- Male announcer: TED NELSON,
A SCIENTIST WHO STUDIED
UNDER THE TWO CULT PIONEERS
VANNEVAR BUSH AND JOHN C. LILLY,
EXPANDED ON THEIR THEORIES.
HE PROPOSED A GIANT
ELECTRONIC LIBRARY
IN SATELLITES
IN STATIONARY ORBIT
WHICH COULD BE USED
AT ANY TERMINAL ON EARTH
VIA RADIO
AND TELEPHONE LINES.
HE CALLED THIS
DARING CONCEPT
THAT WOULD MAKE AN INTERACTIVE
GLOBAL DATABASE A REALITY
"XANADU,"
AFTER THE MYTHICAL COUNTRY...
ALSO KNOWN AS
"THE MONGOLIAN UTOPIA"
WHERE ALL WRITTEN CULTURES
WOULD BE FOREVER PRESERVED
AND LIVE ON
FOR ALL ETERNITY.
THIS WAS XANADU.
AND SO IT WAS THE INNOVATIVE
CONCEPT CALLED "HYPERTEXT"
THAT WOULD FINALLY
MAKE IT A REALITY.
AND TED NELSON'S NAME
WOULD GO DOWN IN HISTORY
AS ITS ESTEEMED
ORIGINATOR.
- HELLO, NAVI.
CLICK-CLICK,
CLICK-CLICK.
MEMORY CHECK.
CLICK-CLICK, CLICK-CLICK,
CLICK-CLICK.
THAT'S ME, ISN'T IT?
- YES, THIS IS ME.
- SURE.
THEN WHO ARE THEY?
TELL ME.
- BUT THERE'S NO WAY
FOR ME TO KNOW THAT,
BECAUSE I'M YOU.
- THIS IS A LIE.
IT HAS TO BE.
IT'S A LIE,
ALL OF IT.
I DON'T GET IT.
WHY ARE YOU
DOING THIS TO ME?
- Male announcer: THE EARTH,
WHILE ORBITING THE SUN,
HAS ITS OWN SPECIFIC
ELECTROMAGNETIC WAVES.
BETWEEN THE IONOSPHERE
ON THE EARTH'S SURFACE,
THERE IS A CONSTANT
RESONANCE
AT A FREQUENCY
OF EIGHT HERTZ
IN THE E.L.F. BAND RANGE
OF FREQUENCIES.
THIS IS CALLED
"THE SCHUMANN RESONANCE."
HOWEVER, THE EXTENT OF
THE EFFECT ON HUMAN SUBJECTS
OF THESE EARTH BRAIN WAVES THAT
THE PLANET CONSTANTLY GIVES OFF
IS IMPOSSIBLE TO QUANTIFY
AND REMAINS A MYSTERY.
THE HUMAN POPULATION
OF THE EARTH IS APPROACHING
THAT OF THE NUMBER
OF NEURONS IN THE BRAIN.
DOUGLAS RUSHKOFF PROPOSES
THAT THE CONSCIOUSNESS
OF THE EARTH ITSELF
MIGHT BE AWAKENED
WHEN ALL HUMANS ON EARTH
BECOME COLLECTIVELY NETWORKED
AND RESONATE
AT THE SAME FREQUENCY.
THE EVOLUTION
OF THE NETWORK
WOULD FOLLOW
A NEURAL MODEL PATH.
AND JUST AS NEURONS
WITHIN THE HUMAN BRAIN
ARE CONNECTED
BY SYNAPSES,
THE EARTH ITSELF WOULD BECOME
A SINGLE NEURAL NETWORK.
- THERE IS ONLY
ONE REAL TRUTH
AND ONE GOD.
- ( male voice )
YES-- ME.
- Male announcer:
MASAMI EIRI,
CHIEF RESEARCHER
AT TACHIBANA GENERAL LABS,
FURTHER DEVELOPED THE HYPOTHESIS
OF A WORLDWIDE NEURAL NETWORK.
HIS HYPOTHESIS PROPOSED
THIS WIRELESS NETWORK
WHEREBY ALL OF HUMANITY
WOULD BE PLUGGED IN
AT AN UNCONSCIOUS LEVEL
WITHOUT THE NEED
FOR ANY TECHNICAL SUPPORT
OR ANCILLARY DEVICE.
FURTHERMORE,
HE CAREFULLY ENCODED
THE SCHUMANN RESONANCE FACTOR
AND INSERTED IT INTO
THE SEVENTH-GEN WIRED PROTOCOL
ON HIS OWN INITIATIVE.
UPON DISCOVERING THIS,
TACHIBANA GENERAL LABS
DISMISSED EIRI.
ONE WEEK LATER,
MASAMI EIRI'S BODY
WAS FOUND ALONGSIDE THE TRACKS
ON THE YAMANOTE TRAIN LINE.
- ( theme song playing )
nan no tsumi mo nai hazu na no ni nanraka no batsu wo uketeru
Although I must be innocent, now I am punished
jibun de maita tane de mo nai no ni
I wasn't the one who sowed those seeds, but nevertheless
sakimidareta hana tsumasareru
I have to pull up the flowers that bloomed from them
shiranai koto to mo ienai ga
I can't say I didn't know about it
katabou katsuida oboe wa nai
but I don't remember taking any part in it
jiyuu wo takaku kawasareta ki mo suru ga
I think my freedom cost me dearly
kokoro made yasuku utta oboe wa nai
but I don't remember selling my soul so cheaply
hey hey kutabatte osaraba suru made
Hey hey, until I die and say farewell...
hey hey dare no te ni mo kakaranai
Ey ey... nadie puede tocarme
vagando por la noche lejana
Probablemente no sabes
shiranai darou eien no narazu monotachi wo
los bandidos eternos merodeando en la noche lejana